I'll now call to order the regular meeting of the Minor City Council for Tuesday, June 17.
Two public input and on the scheduled personal appearances.
Three action addicts.
Jones, I.
Furns.
Parker.
I.
East.
Number four claims for the man's auto group.
So again.
Jones.
I.
Furns.
Parker.
East.
I.
Number five action minutes from the May 2025.
Regular meeting May 2020.
May 27 regular meeting and June 3rd.
Regular meeting.
Jones.
Parker.
Furns.
I.
East.
Number six.
Budget amendment for.
A lot of things.
There's a paragraph here.
So I'm just going to trust that everything that's in here.
This public knowledge.
If anybody wants to read anything.
Looking up on.
This is the first year we had someone trained at.
Was not one water or like or is that someone else's work up to.
To ensure to be.
And they wanted that back in there.
Uh budget.
Uh it also has the library.
We're receiving an extending.
Grants.
I should write to them.
Come.
Let's thank the 23777.
That is for your sales tax incentive program.
So we have.
But contract with one company.
We give them back 75% of the.
the sales tax rate pay for either five years or $50,000.
This is the second year, first full of years.
That was 10.
All right.
Number seven, outside,
we're going to take some feedback to provide services for fiscal year 2526
for Community Crisis Center,
Grand Gateway, Peleban,
Miami Area Economic Development Service.
It's the same contract set for the Commission rate,
but on the Peleban,
it's for a cash payment with 46,000
that is what they're requesting for the application.
Number seven, outside,
20 split up between the main, it is a $50,000 cash payment and the main $20,000 credit
up to the next base and the two of that.
Jones, I think.
My character.
Okay.
Hi.
Uh, line nine, eight discussion and action requests for the approval of the Miami Main Street
logo.
Trinda.
We have a new logo.
We've ran this approved, uh, some leading along there.
So what's the color representation?
Is it just random?
No.
It's taken off your wallet.
She's in that clothes.
That's where he went.
Yeah.
And the copy that you have made to be is not occurred within those lines.
And this one.
See you later.
All right.
Thank goodness you got a $50,000.
Thoughts?
Parts.
Do you know not to vote for it?
I don't know.
If I can, I don't know.
Because I'm on the board.
But I'm sure.
I don't know.
Then I like motion to prove.
All right.
Well done.
Thank you.
Very well done.
It's very well done.
Good job.
All right.
Number nine.
Request for approval of the Senior rebranding is recommended by the MIM Senior
Center for Board.
Melinda and Callie.
Hello.
Senior.
Yeah.
It's fine.
I'm putting kind of this new process for branding.
So what you just saw was the one that went through the money.
Many I can see it should be at final approval so that we have something that hopefully, as if you don't like it, to say something about these designs, but they have us for a process, we have Sean and Bob, he's a designer along your seat, he did not, he's on the end of course, little bit, and so I've been working with him, professional, if you see something, I'll fix it, but I'll just have Kelly explain the one thing.
So Sean came in and put the seniors in our secondary audience as all of us on to include education, energy life, and our new two options present, this was the one.
I'm just different.
Can you tell us how it's greeted you?
So tell us what you're talking about, tell us what this represents and how you grew up with this.
So all those, all those little logos and represent are representing it.
Those all logos, they just had that, and all represented in this.
So all four of those, they're in there, that's why I drew the things.
So we went in there probably that were involved in a discussion they each ran on everything which are
I'm like to commend you on getting this done in an hour
I've seen well those that take days and weeks to design
Okay
Great place
So one of them is not and so
Sean is also he's like a great community partner
I've got even involved in this
We're spending the stuff down because he said he went out so we've got him on board and work in professional
I think they've also used like an a deal in art piece
From when I do great stuff if you haven't seen this work is the commerce
One on the side of the division post so he's doing some neural work around here I'm trying to
a little bit
Anyway, so we think this will really cool it's best to look like a bigger part of it
Which I thought was the coolest part for me
What's it? Well, it's not your same old senior server. We've got a lot of new stuff going there
So just kind of rebranding is a thing this is a big time for it on the city
If it had a great deal to do this work it's from professional work cost a lot of money
I do graphics but I just want to do some merit because we choose to
You want something or something I see it, you're going to have another thing that's weird about it.
You're helping to spend monumental in this, when you have somebody that's a branding and marketing expert,
basically the process that you described right there.
And I described it in the meetings kind of jokingly, but it really translated well.
You used to take like the quizzes and 17 magazine to see what kind of husband you were going to have.
I know you guys know, but that's pretty much what it is.
But to get the feedback of all the seniors and you know, they played a protective role in creating this,
you know, definitely.
I think all like that.
But you should make things easier.
We didn't have a fight.
A collaboration of all the thoughts of everybody that's there.
So we really need to see their thoughts, turn into an actual piece of art.
And we're so grateful for that.
We have a much less thought part as part of everybody in the room.
And that's what it comes down to.
If you just ask everybody the opinion, you're going to have 30 different opinions.
When you have an actual iceberg coming, that has those skills to focus to do for the first day,
there's a lot of opinions there.
Again, the process that I want is for branding for it to go through the advisors more than her, you know,
the appropriate counsel for a little bit of the state.
I was going to talk to you.
Does anybody adding in a establishment you're on the other side there?
Just a thought.
I'm going to pay you a week.
I'm going to share a year to share a year to share a year to share a year to share a year to share a year.
I think they're here.
It was established, I think.
I'm not that's just, I'm asking.
I'm not.
I understand that, you know, this was brought to everybody's attention and everybody's pretty much kind of decided that this is the one.
that they feel like really encompasses the senior center.
My question is, you know, I see the colors.
For me, it's not giving senior center vibes for lack of better words, but
and I understand you're trying to correlate the colors with the state.
Is there a reason that we're trying to make that shift?
Is this a second level?
It's trying to get with the state colors rather than city colors.
Does that make sense?
It differentiates us from Florida.
Okay.
If we have the state colors, that was one of the kind of the goals in the discussion.
It was one of my state or do I like to have Oklahoma on it?
Yes.
Right.
Did that like that intentional outside of Miami?
Were there any other designs created besides the one that we have for granted?
It's not obvious if it is marketing.
Well, I was talking to Steve to this to some of that.
It's more so normal and obvious to you.
So in the research, it's been a lot of them, though, that.
You know, it was similar to the one in the other option daily, it was similar to the one I saw, and that's what it was going at the end.
Why does it receive a one at tree?
Or a tree?
What do you mean?
I don't know.
Tree, leaves, hugers.
Look tired.
I don't know.
I can actually thank you.
I hate to be like, I don't like it.
Because I know it's gone through a lot of, I mean, a lot of experts, a lot of research behind it.
And I mean, at the end of the day, the board has approved it, and that's what they feel like represents that center.
And I'm not going to be the one that's staying in the way.
I just for me.
This is like feisty those local. I don't think so see your center. I don't think for me
It's I think it's maybe the pin shit as a shape of it. I don't know
But for me, it's not grabbing my attention saying oh, that's a senior stand. Let's go check that out
But that's just my opinion and again like you've stated
I mean everybody's gonna have a different opinion and I don't want to be the one standing the way of it
So I mean the boards cool with it those who
Members are cool with it then
They're for law
That's I can see where it's gone from two because low those are our change
But you have one that's our change because it's on everything
And I hate to say that too because I will have any side as clue as to what
Like any suggestions. I'm okay. How about this? How about this, but so and not to describe it. You're work either. I think this is great
I would every well go to create
And here in as why I said I'm command you for that hour use for it
I'm going to make a motion when I prove so I'm going to put it to it.
People can't.
I'm not even, you're not putting canes on it or it's not.
It's detailed.
I just need to send this.
E-step.
Parker?
Five.
Jones?
The same.
Barnes.
She's sitting here.
Will we work it and bring you back to another one?
Does it work?
All right.
Okay.
Action.
Our item number 10.
Regarding renewal of the doc services contract and rental agreement with senior center.
I'll throw as a student manager to sign.
This is a contract that we've pushed out a little bit better.
We feel like the previous contracts now as everybody knows the senior center is new to the city.
It's a new acquisition.
So in previous and days gone by, the city paid the rent for doc services to use the kitchen.
And now that the city has acquired the facility,
we are responsible for the maintenance, the upkeep, the expense of running the thing.
And we, that it's time that they start paying rent.
The contract contains $1,000 per month.
And they pay the utilities.
And I think we agree to pay the trash.
We pay the trash in full.
And of course we would have to do.
We'll have to comply with landlord and law as far as upkeep and all of that.
But that is sort of factor into the contract to establish a rent.
The contracts have always said that they are to pay $1,000 a month rent.
It's just that they have not had to pay that.
The agency has not because the city paid it for it.
So, that is contract really as a different situation where they will be paying their own rent.
And this was also recommended by the senior board.
Yes, it's worth the four of it.
Some of the docs service is folks aware of this.
Yes.
And they're budgeted for it.
That's something we're going to have to start the conversation with.
I mean, I know.
You know, we have someone here that you still work at a different light and job.
And, you know, they had money then to pay rent.
You know, when we're going through all that.
So, I know, of course, so I made them aware.
That we are looking for.
The docs service is folks.
So they saw their own board.
Take shit.
They're not going to put it in gateway, aren't they?
Yeah.
Kevin can probably help us.
I will tell you that since the stage been involved, we started looking more and more in the web kitchen.
And just some of the repairs we had.
We had an air conditioner go down.
And just their kitchen.
The counselor about half of the entire building built for six years.
Makes sense.
We've got to walk in.
Yeah.
It's hard when you're doing all the repairs and all the night.
That's.
Did you pay for it when you.
Agreed.
And we can get it.
Well, and things have changed because before we were up to the ramp,
there's our partnership.
And we weren't happy to end up.
People in the building and all that stuff.
Now we're building.
So that's kind of changed.
And we cannot.
Say your senior center.
Employees cannot be in their at all.
Yeah.
So they can't use that kitchen even when dogs are not used right.
We all are well aware of the.
Situation at the senior center.
Kitchener.
Okay.
We were we went through a whole lot of or pain and suffering over.
The legality across the threshold of that kitchen.
That's very, very crystal clear to all of us.
That's why I was asking about them.
If they if they were aware of it and if they're bored.
Cause next.
If we pass this the next meeting we have.
I can guarantee you somebody from there's going to be here.
They know a contract is coming.
We wanted to get your support before we set that.
Yeah.
I'm.
I support 100%.
I agree with everything that was said.
Any other questions?
Please.
I'd like to mention to a pre or a commivore with the contract and written.
Make the offer to them.
I'll second.
Parker?
Aye.
E step.
Jones.
Marks?
Aye.
Okay.
Item 11.
The clear.
The Miami PD Motors.
Oh, sorry.
The clear.
The Miami PD drone.
Equip an included in the packet of surplus and authorize the items.
To be offered to sell to wind out nation PD or online auction.
Give a latest sign of authority to the city manager.
Does it mean?
Yeah.
So is this the one that we used to track down people or is the one we have?
Have that capability.
So we have to do.
This one is.
We set up thermal imaging capability with the one we're planning on keeping in all that.
Sounds easy to meet.
And if we do this.
We'll need to do it in our ages.
Jones.
Part-time.
Part piece.
All right.
Item 12.
The clear.
The Miami PD Motor Cycles fleet included in the packet of surplus and authorize the
items we offer for sale of donation.
The related sign of authority to the city manager.
Where he's designated.
Two items.
Two houses.
I know she's done that.
I'm excited.
You get budget clear tonight and you're here to help me.
I make a mission to approve.
Barnes, Jones, hi.
Parker.
Hi.
Thank you, Jennifer.
Thank you.
Actually, I'm number 13.
Mayor Salmonation to re-appoint Jodale Morgan to the
Minedown Townery Development Authority, Term to expire.
7, 2, 28.
This, our orbit says that the mayor is to nominate the appointees to this board.
The trust in the interest has otherwise.
So Melissa asked me how I wanted to do it and we don't have time to fix it and we need
the marks on the shoulder.
Leave it the way that it's always been until we do it this work out.
I'm not talking to each one of them.
So we have two members on the board.
Okay.
So we're going to table on on 13 and table on on 14.
We apologize for that.
We just realized that just setting up here when we started.
Putting it all together.
That's easy.
All right.
15 potential action items of the new business, which is a
risen system post and this agenda.
We have none.
Number 16 staff reports.
17 mayor and county council committee announcements.
Last week.
One thank everybody for allowing me to go to the mayor's conference last week.
And I'm sitting from in the city.
I'm in the city.
I'm in the good week.
And I'll get talks.
A lot of stuff that's in the middle of mind.
I'll forward half in there.
And that work team is worth it.
And something like that.
I really hope that the council would like to go with me at some point for
some of these because there's stuff that everybody will learn.
So I'm coming up in September.
I should be bigger than some of the council.
Smaller.
But council is always about to go.
It's a matter.
It's about to go.
Other staffs.
There's also about to go to different things.
There may be less.
I think Molly will have a list of everything.
It's all for today.
One in September.
And.
So I think my wants to go against that different Tyler if he doesn't take them or not, but
If you count whenever you would like to go another heavy because there's a lot to be learned you'll you'll see that we're not in this boat alone
It's funny when we go there because we hear about how bad our streets are
Every mayor there here's the same thing
That they've got the worst streets in town and they've got too many tweakers around and they've got, you know, their parks look horrible is it's it's
It's comfortable but it's not because we have a lot of the same issues but you also get to find out some ways that they handle things
And it's maybe different what we tried so we come back and implement some of that stuff
There's also vendors there, my brought some stuff back to Crystal that I thought may be important and we'll let her tell somebody is or not
But it was a good week, so I appreciate GSM, this time we got to do a tour to kick her out for space
We're just going to go to the commander and ran to Commander, he just came in on my day, we were there on Wednesday
So he was going to go fire hose, but he took us on the tour
And the cool thing was his sister, my commander, really cool
How was her?
I don't know
But it was a cool event, so I appreciate you guys letting me go
And the staff, I know, I've been reading Facebook not today, so I can't read anything
But, and I've seen, you know, we've got 15 or 20 people in this community that are not going to be happy with anything
But there's 13,000, some of others, they appreciate what you do
And ignore those 20, those 20 have no clue what goes into what we do
And they definitely don't want to have clue what goes into what you do
You know, we just read it a parking lot that need to be done for several years
And of course you got those 20 out there
You know, saying that you haven't done the truck route, they have no idea that those two don't correlate with one of them
Other price wise and I can close
So just keep doing what you do, one has done a great job, shielding everybody from that small group
But I appreciate everything you guys do, just keep being keep doing what you're doing
And mom doesn't keep wanting to keep moving forward
And people up here have her back, so just keep going
There's one of the police department they right now, cheers to them
That is hilarious and I love every minute of it, it's please keep that go
I noticed it has been hard
Yes, yes, I think that that's well played
I'll go to Wendy's Twitter page and get some ideas
The other announcements?
Item number 18, City Manager Communications.
Yeah, it doesn't have to spend a week about eight, man.
That's all I have to thank you.
Thank you.
19, German.
5, 2, 8, 7.
Alright.